advice to help you with your endurance and your strength.
Peace.
I know you've been told to train your endurance
to improve your health,
but how intense should that actually be?
Research influencers like Rhonda Patrick
and Andrew Huberman will oftentimes improve their endurance
by using four by four minute intervals
and they'll call that the Norwegian protocol.
But what if I told you the real Norwegian protocol
is actually 10 times more effective
and four by four minutes isn't even
in the Norwegian applied training book.
This is how it's done.
You're gonna set a timer for 45 seconds
and you're gonna go hard.
During that 45 seconds,
your heart rate's gonna get to about 85 to 90% of its max.
But then you're gonna take a 15 second break.
During that 15 second break,
now your muscles have enough time to recover.
Here's the kicker.
You're gonna do this for 15 to 20 sets.
Ultimately, we want you to work up to 30 sets.
And you might even be thinking,
there's no way that I can do 20 to 30 sets of cardio.
And you will adapt to this high tempo.
You just need to follow this training day
with a 70% heart rate workout or a nice lifting session.
Follow for more hybrid training advice
to help you with your endurance and your strength.
Peace.
I know you've been told to train your endurance.